[
  {
    "id": "1",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "Which types of waves are utilized in the night visionary equipment?",
    "answer": "Infrared wave"
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "Sound above what level (in decible) is considered hazardous noise pollution?",
    "answer": "80 db"
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "The speed of the sound increases when there is an increase in the ,1. temperature ,2. moisture",
    "answer": "Both 1 & 2"
  },
  {
    "id": "4",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "The speed of the sound increases when there is an increase in the temperature as well as moisture. Speed of the sound increases by 0.61 meter per second for each ° increase in temperature.",
    "answer": "Water"
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "The propagation of the Radio Waves in the atmosphere of earth is affected by ___:, 1. Reflection, 2. Refraction, 3. Diffraction, 4. Absorption",
    "answer": "1, 2, 3 & 4"
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "The branch of mechanics which deals with the study of motion of material objects without taking into account the factors which cause motion is called as:",
    "answer": "Kinematics"
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "As per the Newtons second law of motion, what is the relation between the rate of change of linear momentum and the external force applied?",
    "answer": "inversely proportional"
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "What is the dimensional formula of Gravitational Potential?",
    "answer": "M0 L2 T-2"
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "What is the time period for a satellite orbiting close to the surface of earth?",
    "answer": "84.6 minutes"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "subject": "physics",
    "question": "In which of these transistors, the two segments of n-type semiconductor are separated by a segment of p-type semiconductor?",
    "answer": "n-p-n transistor"
  },

  {
    "id": "11",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "The purest form of iron is ",
    "answer": "wrought iron"
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "Hydrogen bomb is based on the principle of ",
    "answer": "nuclear fusion"
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "What is the molecular formula of Butyne",
    "answer": "c4H6"
  },
  {
    "id": "14",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "What is the IUPAC name for the following compound? H3C _ C≡C _ H",
    "answer": "Methyl acetylene"
  },
  {
    "id": "15",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "How many molecules are present in one mole of water?",
    "answer": "6.02 x 1023 molecules"
  },
  {
    "id": "16",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "Brass gets discoloured in air because of the presence of which of the following gases in air  ?",
    "answer": "Hydrogen sulphide"
  },
  {
    "id": "17",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "Is C2 Paramagnetic or Diamagnetic?",
    "answer": "Diamagnetic"
  },
  {
    "id": "18",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "Which of the following group is NOT Dobereiner Triads?",
    "answer": " N, P , Au"
  },
  {
    "id": "19",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "Name the Scientist who stated that matter can be converted into energy",
    "answer": " Einstein"
  },
  {
    "id": "20",
    "subject": "chemistry",
    "question": "When formaldehyde and potassium hydroxide are heated , we get ",
    "answer": "Methyl alcohol"
  },
  {
    "id": "21",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "A ripe Tomato is Red, Leaves are Green, Flower is Purple, Hair is Black. Bring out the pigments responsible for these colors respectively ?",
    "answer": "[Lycopene, Chlorophyll, Anthocyanin, Melanin]"
  },
  {
    "id": "22",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "Turmeric belongs to from which one of the following family of plants?",
    "answer": "Ginger"
  },
  {
    "id": "23",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "The biological nature of the virus came from studies by the Russian scientist ____ in 1892 and by the Dutch scientist ____ in 1898.",
    "answer": "[Dmitry I. Ivanovsky, Martinus W. Beijerinck]"
  },
  {
    "id": "24",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "How many amino acids are needed to make proteins?",
    "answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "id": "25",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "The region where the leaves arise is__.",
    "answer": "nodes"
  },
  {
    "id": "26",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "External ears are characteristics of:",
    "answer": "Mammals"
  },
  {
    "id": "27",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "Breathing, heartbeat, sleep, wakefulness, and motor learning are controlled by which part of the brain?",
    "answer": "Hindbrain"
  },
  {
    "id": "28",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "Why is excretion a vital process in the human body?",
    "answer": "because it helps to remove the waste products from the body"
  },
  {
    "id": "29",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "Name the hardest material present in the body",
    "answer": "Enamel"
  },
  {
    "id": "30",
    "subject": "biology",
    "question": "Which gland is considered as the Third eye of the body or biological clock of the body?",
    "answer": "Pineal gland"
  },
  {
    "id": "31",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "MS-Word is an example of _____",
    "answer": "Application software"
  },
  {
    "id": "32",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "Ctrl, Shift and Alt are called .......... keys.",
    "answer": "modifier"
  },
  {
    "id": "33",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "A computer cannot boot if it does not have the _____",
    "answer": "Operating system"
  },
  {
    "id": "34",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "________ is the process of dividing the disk into tracks and sectors",
    "answer": "Formatting"
  },
  {
    "id": "35",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "Junk e-mail is also called ______",
    "answer": "Spam"
  },
  {
    "id": "36",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "Where is RAM located?",
    "answer": "Mother Board"
  },
  {
    "id": "37",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "What is the Full Form of INTERNET ?",
    "answer": "Internet' is the shortened form of 'INTERnational-NETwork' which is the interconnected network of all the Web Servers worldwide. It is often called the 'World Wide Web'"
  },
  {
    "id": "38",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "The function of BIOS is to",
    "answer": "Initialize the system hardware components"
  },
  {
    "id": "39",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "The first computer was programmed using .......",
    "answer": "Machine language"
  },
  {
    "id": "40",
    "subject": "computer",
    "question": "C, BASIC, COBOL, and Java are examples of ............language",
    "answer": "high-level"
  }
]
